Seems like forever
Since the four of us have been out to eat   you know?
Just the guys.
Oh   god! Yes   we get it.
You have a girlfriend now.
A little jealous   sorry?
No   I'm not jealous.
All right   I'd kill a hobo if it'll get me laid.
Now   can we order?
Oh   dear lord   they re-did the menu.
So what? It's the same food.
Oh   is it? Look at this.
General tso's chicken
Is no longer listed under "Specialties."
It's now under "Chicken."
So?
Yes   general tso.
Not "Tso  " The chicken   "So" The question.
So?
So   why is it no longer a specialty?
Did the chef lose confidence
In the dish or himself?
And look over here.
"Shrimp in mobster sauce."
What is "Mobster sauce"?
It's obviously a typo.
Perhaps. Or perhaps this restaurant's
Now a front for organized crime.
For all we know   the mobster sauce
Contains actual chunks of deceased mobsters.
No   no   no   no-- I think it just means
It's the kind of sauce that mobsters like.
It doesn't mean any of that!
It's a typo.
You know what? Let's just get a pizza.
Good idea. We'll go to corleone's.
Sure   no mobsters there.
You know   the more I think about it
the mobster sauce couldn't possibly contain
chunks of mobster.
And why is that?
It was listed under "Seafood."
What if they were mobsters who slept with the fishes?
Leonard   are we having a serious conversation or not?
What the...?
The tv is gone.
So are our laptops.
Oh   god.
Oh   god!
It's all right.
They didn't take my comic books.
They took our TV
Two laptops
Four external hard-drives
Our PS2   our PS3
Our x-box   our x-box 360
Our classic nintendo
Our super nintendo   our nintendo 64 and our wii.
We like games.
Right   games. They took halo 1
Halo 2   halo 3   call of duty 1
Call of duty 2   call of duty 3
Rock band   rock band 2
Final fantasy 1 thru 9   the legend of zelda
The legend of zelda: ocarina of time
The legend of zelda: twilight princess
Super mario brothers   super mario galaxy
Mario and sonic at the winter olympics...
...and ms. Pacman.
Assorted video games.
When does the csi team get here?
What?
In anticipation of their arrival
I've bagged some evidence.
One of the thieves had the audacity
To quench his thirst while ransacking our home.
You should be able to pull some good prints off this.
And now   here are my prints
So you can rule me out as a suspect.
What about me?
I'm sorry   leonard. It's too early to discount
The possibility of this being an inside job.
Would I be completely out of line to ask you to shoot him?
I'd be happy to put him under a 72-hour
Psychiatric hold.
I'm not crazy.
My mother had me tested.
We're done here.
Call this number   and we'll fax you a copy of the report
So you can submit it to your insurance company.
I-I'm sorry.
That's the end of your inquiry?
Do you have any more information that might be relevant?
Oh   my goodness. Where do I begin? For instance--
My laptop contained
four out of the five gedankenexperiments
necessary for a cogent restatement
of the quantum measurement problem.
How is that going to help them?
They could monitor scientific publications and see
if anyone posts such a cogent restatement in the next
Couple of months. If so
The authors are most likely
in possession of my stolen laptop.
Good night   fellas.
Come on   Bochco.
What are we supposed to do now?
The only thing we can do.
Watch tv on our phones until the criminals return
and bludgeon us to death in our sleep.
Does that mean you've ruled me out as a suspect?
Oh   how I wish I could.
I do not have to urinate.
I am the master of my own bladder.
Drat.
I can't believe it.
If I hadn't been working the dinner shift
I would've run right into the robbers.
Hey   there's no reason for you to be scared.
I'm not scared.
I would've gone all Nebraska on their asses.
Leonard and Penny.
Hand me the bat.
We just had a major crime in the building
And you open the door without asking who it is?
It won't happen again. What's up?
Nothing.
I just wanted to see if you were both okay.
We're fine   Sheldon.
All right   then.
- Good night.  - Good night.
That was weird   even for him.
Leonard and Penny.
Who is it?
Sheldon. Sheldon Cooper.
Yes?
May I come in?
Yeah.
I see you're drinking wine.
Yes   we are.
And we're about to go to bed.
Sheldon   do you want to sleep here tonight?
Oh   as small as Leonard is
I don't think the two of you'd be comfortable on the couch.
What do you want?
It's not what I want   it's what evolution wants.
Human beings are primates.
Primates have evolved to live in groups
both for protection and support.
But you don't like other people.
I do tonight.
It's scary over there.
It's getting scary here   too.
three little kittens?
Three little pigs?
God   I don't know.
Star Wars?
Did we win? Can we go to bed?
Good lord-- I could not have made this easier.
Hydrogen atom   h
Plus pigs minus pea-- higgs.
Bow   General Zod trapped in the phantom zone.
Bow-zone.
Pear. Tickle.
Pear-tickle.
Higgs boson particle.
How could you not get that?
He's right   penny. It's all there.
Sheldon   sweetie   I know you're feeling insecure
But we've really got to go to sleep.
All right. I'll take the first watch
And wake you at 0400.
Great. Good night.
Wait   wait-- what's 0400?
- 4:00 a.M. - That's   like   in 45 minutes.
Just keep walking.
it's quiet out there.
Maybe a little too quiet.
Where are you going?
Just gonna take a look around outside.
Bad idea.
No   jim   don't open the door!
Listen to her   Jim.
Don't worry.
There's no one out there.
Leonard and Penny!
Who is it?
All right   we've got a titanium dead bolt
And a reinforced jamb
controlled by a state-of-the-art electronic access system.
What if they cut the power?
There's a 200-watt uninterruptible
backup power supply.
What if someone steals my keys?
There are independent voice and fingerprint scanners.
What if someone kidnaps me   forces me to record my voice
and then cuts off my thumb?
I'll send them a basket of muffins.
Now   inside   we've got motion detectors
infrared sensors   and cameras connected to a server
running state-of-the-art facial recognition software.
Where did you get all this stuff?
Eh   I got a buddy over at the Department of Defense.
He just gave it to you?
I'm sure he would have if I had asked.
Ironically   their security
isn't all that good.
Raj   your car is blocking me...
Intruder alert   intruder alert.
- Intruder alert.  - What the hell?
- Intruder alert.  - Sorry   let me help you.
Wonderful security system
If we're attacked by a school of tuna.
Don't worry   the net's going to be electrified.
You picture her on the floor   spasming uncontrollably.
Better.
Sheldon's journal.
Security system in place.
However   sleep continues to elude me.
I've seen the underbelly of Pasadena...
This so-called city of roses   and it haunts me.
Ah   the injustice.
I lie here awake   tormented
while out there evil lurks
probably playing Donkey Kong on my classic Nintendo.
Oh   dear.
I am the master of my own bladder.
Leonard and Penny.
Oh   my...
God   Sheldon.
What the hell are you doing out there?
I heard a noise.
It was us.
We knocked over a lamp.
Why would you knock over a lamp?
- We were going to have...  - He doesn't need
to know what we were doing   Leonard.
No   she's right   I don't need to know what you were doing.
Carry on.
What are you doing?
Use the door.
Good thinking.
Perhaps I'll check the perimeter
and make some warm milk.
Great   you do that.
Would you like me to bring you some warm milk?
I'm lactose intolerant.
And you don't wish to alarm me with any more loud noises.
Very thoughtful.
Warm milk   Penny?
No   thanks.
Fine.
Good night to you   sir.
Miss.
Sorry about that.
Ugh   what can you do?
Here.
Intruder alert   intruder alert.
Looks like Wolowitz got the net electrified.
Sheldon   are you okay?
I-I'm fine...
Although I'm no longer the master of my own bladder.
My new computer came with windows 7.
Windows 7 is much more user-friendly than windows vista.
I don't like that.
Don't you think looking for a new city to live in
is a bit of an overreaction?
Our apartment was broken into
Our security system tried to kill me
And as a result   I'm leaving Pasadena forever.
Tell me how that's overreacting.
Come on   Sheldon   you can't move.
Don't you need to stay in one place
so the mother ship can find you
when it returns?
Oh   if that were only true.
Unfortunately   as I'm earthbound for the foreseeable future
I need to find a location that's more hospitable
than the mean streets of Pasadena   like...
Enid   Oklahoma.
Low crime rate
and high-speed internet connectivity...
But no model train shops.
Sorry   Enid.
Is he quitting his job at the university?
Oh   no   he's going to telecommute.
Everybody's really excited about it.
All right.
Boone   North Carolina.
"Every summer since 1952
Boone has hosted an outdoor amphitheater portrayal
Of the life and times of its namesake   Dan'l Boone."
Sounds like something that would attract the wrong crowd.
Penny   you're from Nebraska   correct?
Born and raised.
It will take me a few days to get settled.
After I do   I will e-mail you detailed PDFs
containing diagrams and instructions
that will guide you through packing and shipping
the rest of my possessions to Bozeman   Montana.
In the meantime   please forward my mail.
Any place specific
Or just the Bozeman   Montana loony bin?
I sense you're making a joke
But Bozeman does have a comedy club called the loony bin
so do not forward my mail there.
Oh   come on.
So you were the victim of a crime.
That's part of life.
When my great-grandfather first came to this country
he put all his hopes and dreams
Into this little butcher shop he ran
on the lower east side of New York.
You know what happened?
Every customer who walked into that butcher shop
and asked for a pound of liver
got ripped off.
But...
Those people moved on   and so should you.
I am moving on.
I'm going to be a Bozite.
They call themselves "Bozites"?
They should. It's one of the first things
I plan to bring up upon arrival.
Sheldon   I can't believe I'm saying this
But I'm going to miss you.
Penny   as you know   I'm not comfortable
with prolonged good-byes and maudlin displays of emotion
so I prepared a short video.
Greetings.
As you know   I'm not comfortable with prolonged good-byes
and maudlin displays of emotion
so I prepared this short video.
The four of you are three of my closest friends
and one treasured acquaintance.
Though I cannot state categorically that my life
will be diminished by not having you in it
I am comfortable if you choose to believe that.
Since you intend to remain
in this lawless metropolitan area
statistics suggest that you will succumb to tragic
and gruesome ends before we meet again.
Live long and prosper.
Sheldon   that's so...
You might want to lock the door behind me.
This isn't Bozeman.
How the hell do I know who's the friend
and who's the acquaintance?
That is a bracing cold
An invigorating cold.
Lord   is it cold!
Help you with your bags   sir?
Thank you   fellow Bozite.
And may I say   you are the living embodiment of all
the promises made by our lovely town's chamber of commerce.
Wait!
Excuse me!
One ticket to Pasadena   California   please.
Hey   look who's back!
Interesting.
The acquaintance is the first to greet me.